{
    "time": 30,
    "maxQuestions": 50,
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "One of the following is the MOST ploughed source of funds for women entrepreneurs",
            "options": [
                "personal assets and savings",
                "personal loans",
                "bank financing",
                "loans from friends/business associations"
            ],
            "correctOption": "personal assets and savings"
        },
        {
            "question": "The LEAST favoured “business” started by women entrepreneurs are;",
            "options": [
                "service related",
                "manufacturing and  construction",
                "oil and gas",
                "high-tech"
            ],
            "correctOption": "manufacturing and  construction"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where is the commercial capital of Nigeria?",
            "options": [
                "Ibadan",
                "Aba",
                "Kano",
                "Lagos"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Lagos"
        },
        {
            "question": "Women more likely than men tend to  _____________ ",
            "options": [
                "have administrative experience",
                "have experience in the field of their ventures",
                "have middle level management experience",
                "have higher level management experience"
            ],
            "correctOption": "have administrative experience"
        },
        {
            "question": "One of the not so obvious obstacles women entrepreneurs face include:",
            "options": [
                "financial obstacles",
                "economic obstacles",
                "soft obstacles",
                "emotional obstacles"
            ],
            "correctOption": "soft obstacles"
        },
        {
            "question": "One of the very  obvious obstacles women entrepreneurs face include: ",
            "options": [
                "financial obstacles",
                "economic obstacles",
                "soft obstacles",
                "emotional obstacles"
            ],
            "correctOption": "financial obstacles"
        },
        {
            "question": " _____________ is an example of a woman entrepreneur: ",
            "options": [
                "Bola Shagaya",
                "Patience Goodluck Jonathan",
                "Fati Abubakar",
                "Evelyn Oputu"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Bola Shagaya"
        },
        {
            "question": "Apart from group of individuals, alliance of organisations, who are those that seek sustainable pattern breaking ideas?",
            "options": [
                "People",
                "Network",
                "Firms",
                "Populace"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Network"
        },
        {
            "question": "Social entrepreneurship exists in; ",
            "options": [
                "Few organisations",
                "Unique organisations",
                "Rare organisations",
                "All organisations"
            ],
            "correctOption": "All organisations"
        },
        {
            "question": "Social entrepreneurship subsists in:",
            "options": [
                "Rare organisation",
                "Few organisations",
                "All organisation",
                "Unique organisations"
            ],
            "correctOption": "All organisation"
        },
        {
            "question": "Social entrepreneurship rarely subsists in which organisation? ",
            "options": [
                "Government",
                "Corporate organisation",
                "Religious sector",
                "Humanitarian sector"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Government"
        },
        {
            "question": "The launching and sustaining of social entrepreneurship unusually begins with:",
            "options": [
                "Group efforts",
                "Global efforts",
                "Personal efforts",
                "Local efforts"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Local efforts"
        },
        {
            "question": "Credibility as an essential characteristic for successful social entrepreneur means:",
            "options": [
                "Ability to tap critical resources and build the necessary network of participating organisation",
                "be truthful and sound",
                "Accountability to the organisation",
                "Integrity and reliability of the person is topmost"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Ability to tap critical resources and build the necessary network of participating organisation"
        },
        {
            "question": "Business entrepreneurs create and transform whole industries while social entrepreneurs ",
            "options": [
                "Create and transform people",
                "Create sustainable solutions that bring social value",
                "Socialize people into their culture",
                "Engage in powerful campaign for funding"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Create sustainable solutions that bring social value"
        },
        {
            "question": "Every activity or effort of social entrepreneurs has global relevance but also has a __________ expression ",
            "options": [
                "State",
                "National",
                "Local",
                "Domestic"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Local"
        },
        {
            "question": "A world view of social entrepreneurship is called ",
            "options": [
                "Amnesty entrepreneurship",
                "World social entrepreneurship",
                "International social entrepreneurship",
                "Regional social entrepreneurship"
            ],
            "correctOption": "International social entrepreneurship"
        },
        {
            "question": "Majority of non-profit organisations target work is on the _______scale?",
            "options": [
                "Immediate",
                "Small-Scale",
                "Medium",
                "Long-term"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Long-term"
        },
        {
            "question": "Continuous development and improvement of knowledge and skills in business can be fostered through",
            "options": [
                "Networking",
                "Social Interaction",
                "Reading",
                "Learning"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Learning"
        },
        {
            "question": "Learning cut across  _____________ sectors",
            "options": [
                "All",
                "Good",
                "Better",
                "Few"
            ],
            "correctOption": "All"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the African context, learning is referred to as  _____________  continuous acquisition of knowledge and skills over time.",
            "options": [
                "Kinship’s",
                "Communities",
                "Individual’s",
                "Heir’s"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Individual’s"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following has NOT been identified (by research) as a personal characteristic that entrepreneurs need in order to succeed?",
            "options": [
                "Strong ethical fibre",
                "Tenacity",
                "Leadership skills",
                "Passion for the cause"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Passion for the cause"
        },
        {
            "question": "The ability to pass on knowledge and skills from one person to another is  _____________  in business succession and continuity.",
            "options": [
                "Not central",
                "Continuous",
                "Central",
                "Difficult"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Central"
        },
        {
            "question": "Learning means permanent life outside _____________ :",
            "options": [
                "Help zone",
                "Comfort zone",
                "True zone",
                "Trust zone"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Comfort zone"
        },
        {
            "question": "The only way today’s entrepreneurs can cope, survive and be successful is to become a?     ",
            "options": [
                "Planner",
                "Competitor",
                "Continual Learner",
                "Networking"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Continual Learner"
        },
        {
            "question": "Decision making is  _____________  process resulting in the selection of a course of action among several alternative scenarios.      ",
            "options": [
                "Mental",
                "Simple",
                "Thinking",
                "Spiritual"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Mental"
        },
        {
            "question": " _____________  means deciding in advance the financial needs of a business to achieve the basic objective of the firm ",
            "options": [
                "Financial management",
                "Financial planning",
                "Financial control",
                "Financial forecasting"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Financial planning"
        },
        {
            "question": "In financial terms, security means",
            "options": [
                "A feeling of having enough money, being safe and securely in profits",
                "When you take money to the bank and deposit it in a secure safe",
                "When you sign a contract with a creditor that he/she can repossess one of your assets should you be unable to pay back",
                "When you are wealthy and can pay back your debts"
            ],
            "correctOption": "When you sign a contract with a creditor that he/she can repossess one of your assets should you be unable to pay back"
        },
        {
            "question": "Being resourceful entails that an entrepreneur  ",
            "options": [
                "Has the ability to apply new ideas to different situations",
                "Has the ability to take risk",
                "Has the ability to be task-oriented",
                "Has the ability to harness resources through sound management"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Has the ability to harness resources through sound management"
        },
        {
            "question": "A facility that is not provided by Government that can be exploited by SMEs is",
            "options": [
                "Concessionary financing",
                "Merger of SMEs/Industry financing agencies",
                "Long term guarantees",
                "Overdraft"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Overdraft"
        },
        {
            "question": "One of the following is a source of fund that is never typically paid back to its creditors ",
            "options": [
                "Venture capital",
                "Grant",
                "Overdraft",
                "People-to-people lending"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Grant"
        },
        {
            "question": "One of the following sources of financing has high interest rate?",
            "options": [
                "Credit card debt",
                "Bank loans",
                "Venture capital",
                "People-to-people lending"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Credit card debt"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is odd?",
            "options": [
                "Merger of SMEs",
                "Long term guarantees",
                "Overdraft",
                "Concessionary financing by government agencies"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Overdraft"
        },
        {
            "question": "A source of fund that is typically not refunded to its creditors is ",
            "options": [
                "Venture capital",
                "Grant",
                "Overdraft",
                "People-to-people lending"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Venture capital"
        },
        {
            "question": "A person that initiates and starts a new venture is popularly known as  ",
            "options": [
                "Entrepreneur",
                "Intrapreneur",
                "Manager",
                "Business guru"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Entrepreneur"
        },
        {
            "question": "The method of generating ideas that calls for listing the major attributes of existing products and modifying each attribute in search of an improved product is ",
            "options": [
                "Focus group",
                "Forced relationship",
                "Attribute listing",
                "Morphological analysis"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Attribute listing"
        },
        {
            "question": "New business idea can best be generated through the following except ",
            "options": [
                "Problem identification",
                "Morphological analysis",
                "Brainstorming",
                "Intuition"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Intuition"
        },
        {
            "question": "Electronic commerce focuses on the use of  ",
            "options": [
                "MBT",
                "ICT",
                "CTI",
                "ITC"
            ],
            "correctOption": "ICT"
        },
        {
            "question": "The term \"e-business\" was coined by IBM’s marketing and Internet teams in ",
            "options": [
                "1987",
                "1995",
                "1996",
                "1999"
            ],
            "correctOption": "1996"
        },
        {
            "question": "Electronic commerce or e-commerce refers to a wide range of online business activities for             ",
            "options": [
                "Peace and service",
                "goods and products",
                "products and services",
                "deals and contacts"
            ],
            "correctOption": "products and services"
        },
        {
            "question": "Three primary processes are enhanced in e-business____________ ,____________  _____________ and____________                                  ",
            "options": [
                "Production processes, Customer-focused processes and Internal management processes",
                "price, promotion and process",
                "customer focused, internal management and place",
                "None of these"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Production processes, Customer-focused processes and Internal management processes"
        },
        {
            "question": "Management theorist____________  believes that process improvements transform business and lead to innovation, and they represent “the change that creates a new dimension of performance” for organizations. ",
            "options": [
                "John Clarke",
                "Peter Drucker",
                "Cantillon Mark",
                "Bart Arte"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Peter Drucker"
        },
        {
            "question": "The primary route by which e-commerce will affect the economy at large is through its impact on ____________ and _____________ ",
            "options": [
                "income and stagnation",
                "productivity and inflation",
                "prices and goods",
                "productivity and income"
            ],
            "correctOption": "productivity and inflation"
        },
        {
            "question": "In _____________  buyers and sellers are gathered together into a single online trading community, reducing search costs even further ",
            "options": [
                "B2B markets",
                "C2C markets",
                "C2G Markets",
                "Mobile commerce"
            ],
            "correctOption": "B2B markets"
        },
        {
            "question": "The type of e-commerce that is characterized by the growth of electronic marketplaces and online auctions is____________ ",
            "options": [
                "C2B",
                "B2B",
                "C2C",
                "C2G"
            ],
            "correctOption": "C2C"
        },
        {
            "question": "E-commerce facilitates organization____________ , wherein small firms depend on “partner” firms for supplies and product distribution to address customer demands more effectively ",
            "options": [
                "circles",
                "system",
                "business",
                "networks"
            ],
            "correctOption": "networks"
        },
        {
            "question": "According to____________ , although the e-Commerce market in Nigeria, is relatively new, it is however growing in fast pace to attract interests of different sectors of the economy ",
            "options": [
                "George Dowell (2004)",
                "Prince Osuagwu (2013)",
                "Mark Dons",
                "Rafael Nadal (2014)"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Prince Osuagwu (2013)"
        },
        {
            "question": "Every business comes out of an _____________ ",
            "options": [
                "idea",
                "opportunity",
                "customs",
                "aspiration"
            ],
            "correctOption": "idea"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which among these is not a source of generating business idea ",
            "options": [
                "customers",
                "competitors",
                "conferences and workshops",
                "None of these"
            ],
            "correctOption": "None of these"
        },
        {
            "question": "____________ technique calls for identifying the structural dimensions of a problem and examining the relationship among them ",
            "options": [
                "Morphological Analysis",
                "Attribute listing",
                "Problem Identification",
                "Brainstorming"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Morphological Analysis"
        },
        {
            "question": "Viable business ideas stem from inspiration, perspiration, and _____________ ",
            "options": [
                "source",
                "techniques",
                "calling",
                "marketing"
            ],
            "correctOption": "techniques"
        },
        {
            "question": "Each of us encounters____________ and____________  of business organizations as we go through the day ",
            "options": [
                "browns and items",
                "products and teaching",
                "products and services",
                "services and competition"
            ],
            "correctOption": "products and services"
        },
        {
            "question": "____________ conceive, born and carry out their business activities in some organized set ups known as business enterprises or organizations ",
            "options": [
                "drivers",
                "servicemen",
                "organizers",
                "entrepreneurs"
            ],
            "correctOption": "entrepreneurs"
        },
        {
            "question": "The sources from which an entrepreneur obtains the funds necessary to start up or operate a business is",
            "options": [
                "Investment",
                "Funding sources",
                "Risk bearing",
                "Financial management"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Funding sources"
        },
        {
            "question": "Grants may be available for entrepreneurial activities from ",
            "options": [
                "Private Foundations or NGOs",
                "Competing organizations",
                "The open market",
                "Government agencies"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Private Foundations or NGOs"
        },
        {
            "question": "____________ is key to sound financing and control that will ensure the relation of the major objective of the finance function",
            "options": [
                "Directing",
                "Controlling",
                "Organizing",
                "Planning"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Planning"
        },
        {
            "question": "When a need is satisfied as investment worthy and a proposal is identified, the next line of action by the entrepreneur is ",
            "options": [
                "Distribution plan",
                "Feasibility study",
                "Financial plan",
                "Production plan"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Financial plan"
        },
        {
            "question": "One source of funding available to the entrepreneur that is not paid back to the creditor is called",
            "options": [
                "Credit card",
                "Grant",
                "People-to-people lending",
                "Venture capital"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Grant"
        },
        {
            "question": " _____________  is financial capital provided to early-stage, high-potential, high risk, growth start-up companies",
            "options": [
                "Grant",
                "Venture capital",
                "Self-finance",
                "People-to-people lending"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Venture capital"
        },
        {
            "question": "A very good guess of the percentage of women business owners in Nigeria is",
            "options": [
                "15%",
                "10%",
                "30%",
                "40%"
            ],
            "correctOption": "15%"
        },
        {
            "question": "Contextual obstacles for women entrepreneurship in Nigeria are",
            "options": [
                "traditional views about women’s role in society",
                "lack of role models to send positive image",
                "women’s perception that they lack entrepreneurship skills",
                "women’s attempting to operate in male dominated fields"
            ],
            "correctOption": "traditional views about women’s role in society"
        },
        {
            "question": "A justification of the study of women entrepreneurship  is because :",
            "options": [
                "they constitute a large segment of the formal sector",
                "they constitute a large segment of the University community",
                "they constitute a large segment of the informal sector",
                "they are our mothers, wives and sisters"
            ],
            "correctOption": "they constitute a large segment of the informal sector"
        },
        {
            "question": "Research indicates most women entrepreneurs DO NOT start out at which age ?:",
            "options": [
                "25-30",
                "31-40",
                "41-45",
                "46 and above"
            ],
            "correctOption": "25-30"
        },
        {
            "question": "____________  is the Governor of Central Bank of Nigeria",
            "options": [
                "Sanusi Lamido Sanusi",
                "Ngozi Okonjo Iweala",
                "Godwin Emefiele",
                "Chukwuma Soludo"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Godwin Emefiele"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the prime aim of decision-making?",
            "options": [
                "Standard achievement",
                "Alternative achievement",
                "Objectives achievement",
                "Process achievement"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Objectives achievement"
        },
        {
            "question": "The most popular method used in generating ideas is?",
            "options": [
                "Brainstorming",
                "Writing",
                "Consultation",
                "Grouping"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Brainstorming"
        },
        {
            "question": "Decision making does allow for level of:",
            "options": [
                "Freedom",
                "Uncertainty",
                "Accuracy",
                "Certainty"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Uncertainty"
        },
        {
            "question": "What helps to look at risk objectively in decision making?",
            "options": [
                "Risk analysis",
                "Risk avoidance",
                "Risk Reduction",
                "Risk identification"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Risk analysis"
        },
        {
            "question": "Cost-Benefit analysis in decision making process helps in:",
            "options": [
                "Time management",
                "Financial Feasibility",
                "Best alternative selection",
                "Project feasibility"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Best alternative selection"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is necessary in decision making?",
            "options": [
                "Contact",
                "Communication",
                "Grape vine",
                "Control"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Communication"
        },
        {
            "question": "The three main responsibilities involved with managing an entrepreneurial ventures once it’s up and running include all of the following except?",
            "options": [
                "Managing processes",
                "Managing growth",
                "Managing Bureaucracy",
                "Managing people"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Managing Bureaucracy"
        },
        {
            "question": "All of the following are recognised as important people practices of successful organisations except:",
            "options": [
                "Employment security",
                "Selective hiring",
                "Increased status differences",
                "Training"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Increased status differences"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is not a characteristic of an effective team?",
            "options": [
                "Clear goals",
                "Irrelevant skills",
                "External support",
                "Mutual trust"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Irrelevant skills"
        },
        {
            "question": "Social entrepreneur sometimes",
            "options": [
                "Quit",
                "fail",
                "Becomes less entrepreneurial",
                "Fight"
            ],
            "correctOption": "fail"
        },
        {
            "question": "The serious barriers faced by social entrepreneurs make them:",
            "options": [
                "Quit",
                "less entrepreneurial",
                "Losers",
                "Sometimes fail"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Sometimes fail"
        },
        {
            "question": "The social mission of a social entrepreneur is:",
            "options": [
                "Implicit & decentralise",
                "Explicit & central",
                "Explicit & decentralise",
                "Implicit & central"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Explicit & central"
        },
        {
            "question": "All political appointees are social entrepreneurs:",
            "options": [
                "Sometimes untrue",
                "Sometimes true",
                "Always true",
                "Always untrue"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Sometimes untrue"
        },
        {
            "question": "The use of  _____________  by social entrepreneurs will not necessarily make them achieve their social objectives:",
            "options": [
                "Market based tools",
                "Planning based tools",
                "Social based tools",
                "Strategic based tools"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Market based tools"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which principle is used in achieving social change?",
            "options": [
                "Management principles",
                "Entrepreneurial principles",
                "Economics principles",
                "Sociological principles"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Entrepreneurial principles"
        },
        {
            "question": "Business entrepreneurs measure performance in profit and return but social entrepreneurs measure performance in:",
            "options": [
                "Social structure",
                "Social change",
                "Social profit",
                "Social returns"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Social change"
        },
        {
            "question": "The highest form of discipline that all persons should develop is?",
            "options": [
                "Unit Discipline",
                "Situational Discipline",
                "Self-Discipline",
                "Cosmic Discipline"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Self-Discipline"
        },
        {
            "question": "Self-discipline relies on self control and a sense of personal",
            "options": [
                "Charm",
                "Responsibility",
                "Awareness",
                "Fear"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Responsibility"
        },
        {
            "question": "Entrepreneurship is the dynamic process of creating:",
            "options": [
                "Economies of scale",
                "Incremental wealth",
                "Mass production",
                "Job opportunities"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Incremental wealth"
        },
        {
            "question": "The development of commerce emerged out of:",
            "options": [
                "Competition",
                "Trading",
                "Specialization",
                "Exportation"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Specialization"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Nigerian economy is traditionally dominated by:",
            "options": [
                "Importation",
                "Agriculture",
                "Commerce",
                "Enterprise"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Agriculture"
        },
        {
            "question": "The first group of entrepreneurs to design and build great pyramids out of stone blocks to laser beans are:",
            "options": [
                "The Greeks",
                "The Chinese",
                "The Dutch",
                "The Egyptians"
            ],
            "correctOption": "The Egyptians"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these entrepreneurs are commonly found in Nigeria?",
            "options": [
                "Craftsman-entrepreneurs",
                "Team builders",
                "Trader-entrepreneurs",
                "Necessity-entrepreneurs"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Trader-entrepreneurs"
        },
        {
            "question": "A celebrated go-between of the old according to history was:",
            "options": [
                "Dangote",
                "Mongo Park",
                "Cantillon",
                "Marco Polo"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Marco Polo"
        },
        {
            "question": "An entrepreneur appears as a threat, and aggressive competitor is the view of",
            "options": [
                "An Economist",
                "A Psychologist",
                "A capitalist",
                "A Businessman"
            ],
            "correctOption": "A Businessman"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these concepts is NOT related to entrepreneurial activities?",
            "options": [
                "Risk taking",
                "Initiative taking",
                "Risk covering",
                "Risk acceptance"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Risk covering"
        },
        {
            "question": "Those who take advantage of other people’s ideas or models to lunch their own     businesses are called:",
            "options": [
                "Necessity Entrepreneurs",
                "Team builders",
                "Independent Inventors",
                "Pattern Multipliers"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Pattern Multipliers"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is Not an essential tool required for enterprising?",
            "options": [
                "Acquisition",
                "Endurance",
                "Empathy",
                "Resourcefulness"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Acquisition"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT a form of business in Nigeria?",
            "options": [
                "Lagos Stock Exchange",
                "Joint Ventures",
                "Partnership",
                "Joint-stock company"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Lagos Stock Exchange"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these factors is NOT a major consideration when a choice of location for a  business is to be made?",
            "options": [
                "The Raw material",
                "The Market",
                "The Capital",
                "The competition"
            ],
            "correctOption": "The Capital"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is a major role of government in an economy where business  activities are healthy?",
            "options": [
                "Consuming",
                "Controlling",
                "Regulating",
                "Participating"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Regulating"
        },
        {
            "question": "________ seeks to determine the viability of an intended business project.",
            "options": [
                "A business Plan",
                "A business Proposal",
                "A feasibility Study",
                "A business Strategy"
            ],
            "correctOption": "A business Proposal"
        },
        {
            "question": "An investigation to determine the success or otherwise of a proposed business is     referred to as:",
            "options": [
                "A Business Proposal",
                "A Business Plan",
                "A Feasibility Plan",
                "A Feasibility Study"
            ],
            "correctOption": "A Business Proposal"
        },
        {
            "question": "Those who create small businesses purposely to survive are called:",
            "options": [
                "Team builders",
                "Independent Inventors",
                "Pattern Multipliers",
                "Necessity Entrepreneurs"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Necessity Entrepreneurs"
        },
        {
            "question": "One of these is NOT an internal variable in business environment:",
            "options": [
                "Assets",
                "Abilities",
                "Tools",
                "Inflation"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Inflation"
        },
        {
            "question": "Economic condition of a country includes:",
            "options": [
                "Demography",
                "Market position",
                "Objectives and goals",
                "Organization"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Demography"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is the most backward activity particularly in Nigeria?",
            "options": [
                "Manufacturing",
                "Production",
                "Marketing",
                "Engineering"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Marketing"
        },
        {
            "question": "The act of obtaining a desired object from another person by offering something in return is referred to as.",
            "options": [
                "Exchange",
                "Distribution",
                "Bargaining",
                "Sourcing"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Exchange"
        },
        {
            "question": "When a hungry person forcibly wrests or steals food from someone else to relieve his hunger, he is engaged in activity called",
            "options": [
                "Exchange",
                "Supplication",
                "Self-production",
                "Coercion"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Coercion"
        },
        {
            "question": "When a hungry person approaches someone and asks for food to relieve his/her hunger, he/she is engaged in activity called",
            "options": [
                "Exchange",
                "Supplication",
                "Self-production",
                "Coercion"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Supplication"
        },
        {
            "question": "One of the following is odd?",
            "options": [
                "A recognized need",
                "Financial support",
                "Competent people with relevant technology",
                "Changes in perception"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Changes in perception"
        },
        {
            "question": "Business enterprises need not to assign functions to financial managers in the areas of planning, procurement and investment.",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False",
                "Nearly true",
                "Not applicable"
            ],
            "correctOption": "False"
        },
        {
            "question": "When a business venture has a sound capital structure. It will lead to a",
            "options": [
                "Profitable business",
                "Mass acquisition of machines",
                "Productive business",
                "Both Profitable business and Mass acquisition of machines only"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Both Profitable business and Mass acquisition of machines only"
        },
        {
            "question": "The following are the limitations of financial planning except",
            "options": [
                "Inadaptability of plans",
                "Reluctance of entrepreneurs to change",
                "Proper coordination",
                "Heavy investments in specialized equipment"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Proper coordination"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which among the following has been identified in many business surveys as the most important factor determining the survival/growth of SMEs in both developing and developed countries?",
            "options": [
                "Materials",
                "Finance",
                "Technology",
                "Information"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Finance"
        },
        {
            "question": "Every business enterprise faces the problem of ____________ of funds to carry on its operations further",
            "options": [
                "Utilization",
                "Investment",
                "Acquisition",
                "Funding"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Funding"
        },
        {
            "question": "A sound capital structure will lead to a",
            "options": [
                "Profitable business",
                "Marketing business",
                "Mass acquisition of machines",
                "Productive business"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Productive business"
        },
        {
            "question": "According to  _____________ , financial planning is the advanced programming of all plans of   financial management and the integration of these plans with the operating plans of the enterprise",
            "options": [
                "Drucker (2000)",
                "Jain (1999)",
                "McKenzy (2004)",
                "Schumpeters (1987)"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Jain (1999)"
        },
        {
            "question": "Grants may be available for entrepreneurial activities from a wide variety of sources except",
            "options": [
                "Federal Government Agencies",
                "Private Foundations or NGOs",
                "State Government Agencies",
                "Competitors"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Competitors"
        },
        {
            "question": "The objective of  _____________   be understood in the light of the enterprise as a whole.",
            "options": [
                "business",
                "financial management",
                "credit",
                "profit"
            ],
            "correctOption": "financial management"
        },
        {
            "question": "Owner’s funds means",
            "options": [
                "Bank loans",
                "Trade credit",
                "Savings",
                "Mortgages"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Savings"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is meant by retained profits?",
            "options": [
                "Profit before all taxes, wages and salaries have been paid",
                "Profits realized after taxes are paid",
                "Profit after all taxes, wages and salaries have been paid",
                "Profits realized after wages are paid"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Profit after all taxes, wages and salaries have been paid"
        },
        {
            "question": "The original source of financing an enterprise is",
            "options": [
                "Self-financing",
                "Bank loans",
                "People-to-people lending",
                "Investment capital"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Self-financing"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which among these is concerned with procurement of funds, assessing needs of funds, raising required funds and financial control?",
            "options": [
                "Financial management",
                "Accounting techniques",
                "Staffing",
                "Investment"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Financial management"
        },
        {
            "question": "____________  _____________ is an overdrawn amount on an account with a bank",
            "options": [
                "Retained profit",
                "Trade credit",
                "Overdraft",
                "Transactional loan"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Overdraft"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these ethnic groups ranked top in terms of entrepreneurial performance in Nigeria on the average as indicated by Harris (1971)?",
            "options": [
                "Hausa",
                "Ibo",
                "Yoruba",
                "Ibibio"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Ibo"
        },
        {
            "question": "Individuals with special ability to plan and execute ceremonies such as weddings, luncheons, etc are called:",
            "options": [
                "Planners",
                "Caretakers",
                "Entertainers",
                "Organizers"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Organizers"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is an external variable in marketing environment?",
            "options": [
                "Decision Structure",
                "Managerial Tools",
                "Political Conditions",
                "Information Resources"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Political Conditions"
        },
        {
            "question": "When a hungry person relieves his hunger through personal efforts, he is engaged in activity called _____________ ",
            "options": [
                "Exchange",
                "Supplication",
                "Self-production",
                "Coercion"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Self-production"
        },
        {
            "question": "One of the following is the least ploughed source of funds for women entrepreneurs;",
            "options": [
                "personal assets and savings",
                "personal loans",
                "bank financing",
                "loans from friends/business associations"
            ],
            "correctOption": "bank financing"
        },
        {
            "question": "A woman entrepreneur is defined also as",
            "options": [
                "business owner-manager",
                "creator-innovator",
                "female entrepreneur",
                "small business woman"
            ],
            "correctOption": "business owner-manager"
        },
        {
            "question": "The MOST favoured “business” started by women entrepreneurs are ;",
            "options": [
                "service related",
                "manufacturing",
                "construction",
                "high-tech"
            ],
            "correctOption": "service related"
        },
        {
            "question": "The process of leaving a scratch on history and causing sea change movements creates?",
            "options": [
                "Social Value",
                "Social Variety",
                "Social Variation",
                "Social Valley"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Social Value"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which one of the following has found new solutions to intractable problems?",
            "options": [
                "Ibrahim Babangida",
                "Victor Adebowale",
                "Goodluck Jonathan",
                "Anyim Pius Anyim"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Victor Adebowale"
        },
        {
            "question": "What Foundation defined social entrepreneur as the “change agents for society, seizing opportunities others miss and improving systems, inventing new approaches and creating sustainable solution to change”?",
            "options": [
                "Schwab foundation",
                "Skoll foundation",
                "Ashoka Foundation",
                "Red-cross Foundation"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Skoll foundation"
        },
        {
            "question": "Disciplining individuals to be industrious is a waste of time.",
            "options": [
                "Sometimes true",
                "Sometimes Untrue",
                "Mostly untrue",
                "Mostly true"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Mostly untrue"
        },
        {
            "question": "What can take the place of persistence?",
            "options": [
                "Talent",
                "Genius",
                "Nothing",
                "Education"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Nothing"
        },
        {
            "question": "The ability to maintain actions regardless of feelings is:",
            "options": [
                "Persistence",
                "Self-discipline",
                "willpower",
                "Acceptance"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Persistence"
        },
        {
            "question": "The ability to move on even when not motivated is:",
            "options": [
                "Acceptance",
                "Willpower",
                "Persistence",
                "Commitment"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Persistence"
        },
        {
            "question": "The External factors that affect business operation include the following except?",
            "options": [
                "Legal system",
                "Social-cultural factors",
                "Ecological factors",
                "Human resources factors"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Human resources factors"
        },
        {
            "question": "Decision-making is solely the responsibility of CEO’s:",
            "options": [
                "Always true",
                "Always untrue",
                "Sometimes true",
                "Sometimes untrue"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Always untrue"
        },
        {
            "question": "Quality control is defined as?",
            "options": [
                "Controlling the cost of the product",
                "Controlling the number of pieces produced",
                "Producing & monitoring products so they are acceptable to the consumer",
                "Producing & monitoring products so they are acceptable to the workers"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Producing & monitoring products so they are acceptable to the consumer"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is least likely to influence the timing of a new business birth?",
            "options": [
                "Government policies",
                "Profitability",
                "Interest rates",
                "Consumer Expenditure"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Profitability"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which one is NOT a step in the problem solving method?",
            "options": [
                "Define the Problem",
                "Gather information",
                "Identify solutions",
                "Ignore the problem"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Ignore the problem"
        },
        {
            "question": "Performance and standard are usually compared in control system of any organisation to prevent:",
            "options": [
                "Coercion",
                "Bad debt",
                "Disaster",
                "Confusion"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Bad debt"
        },
        {
            "question": "Social entrepreneurship rarely subsists in which organisation?",
            "options": [
                "Government",
                "Corporate organisation",
                "Religious sector",
                "Humanitarian sector."
            ],
            "correctOption": "Government"
        },
        {
            "question": "Non-profit organisations use one of the following high performance management practices except:",
            "options": [
                "Political Management",
                "Continuous improvement",
                "Total quality management",
                "Financial management"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Political Management"
        },
        {
            "question": "Social entrepreneurs are individuals alone:",
            "options": [
                "Most often",
                "Most unlikely",
                "Most likely",
                "Most untrue"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Most untrue"
        },
        {
            "question": "Most venture capital comes from all the following except",
            "options": [
                "Group of wealthy investors",
                "Investment banks",
                "Financial institutions",
                "Shareholders"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Shareholders"
        },
        {
            "question": "Every business enterprise faces the problem of ____________ of funds to carry on its operations further",
            "options": [
                "Utilization",
                "Investment",
                "Acquisition",
                "Funding"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Acquisition"
        },
        {
            "question": "A sound capital structure will lead to a____________ ",
            "options": [
                "Profitable business",
                "Productive business",
                "Mass acquisition of machines",
                "Mass production of machines"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Productive business"
        },
        {
            "question": "Grants may be available for entrepreneurial activities from a wide variety of sources except",
            "options": [
                "Federal Government Agencies",
                "Private Foundations or NGOs",
                "State Government Agencies",
                "Self"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Self"
        },
        {
            "question": "Money invested in a business venture with an expectation of income, and recovered through earnings generated by the business over several years is known as",
            "options": [
                "Capital structure",
                "Investment capital",
                "Share capital",
                "Capital contribution"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Investment capital"
        },
        {
            "question": "Any form of capital whether it is obtained through the sales, loans, or equity financing could potentially be viewed as",
            "options": [
                "Share capital",
                "Borrowed capital",
                "Investment capital",
                "Investment market"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Investment capital"
        },
        {
            "question": "The source of funds that is never typically paid back to its creditors is",
            "options": [
                "Venture capital",
                "Grant",
                "Overdraft",
                "People-to-people lending"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Grant"
        },
        {
            "question": "As soon as an entrepreneur certifies that an identified proposal is investment worthy, the next line of action is",
            "options": [
                "Distribution plan",
                "Financial plan",
                "Feasibility study",
                "Production plan"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Production plan"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which is not a facility provided by Government that can be exploited by SMEs?",
            "options": [
                "Concessionary financing",
                "Merger of SMEs/Industry financing agencies",
                "Long term guarantees",
                "Overdraft"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Overdraft"
        },
        {
            "question": "Sources of funds for new ventures are only either",
            "options": [
                "Internal or external",
                "Formal or informal",
                "Both Internal or external and Formal or informal",
                "Private or public"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Both Internal or external and Formal or informal"
        },
        {
            "question": "Self-discipline is developed in business by:",
            "options": [
                "Attention to detail",
                "Not swearing the small stuff",
                "Always being first",
                "Doing whatever you can to get your task done"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Doing whatever you can to get your task done"
        },
        {
            "question": "Self-discipline is developed in business by:",
            "options": [
                "Placing yourself interest ahead of everything",
                "Bribing your way through in deals",
                "Devotion to duty",
                "Laxity"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Devotion to duty"
        },
        {
            "question": "Self-discipline is not developed in business by:",
            "options": [
                "Doing the right thing when no one is watching",
                "Striving to do better than you did before",
                "Achieving set objectives",
                "Always being first"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Always being first"
        },
        {
            "question": "The process of Identifying and defining a problem:",
            "options": [
                "cannot be done until alternatives are proposed",
                "is the first step of decision making",
                "is the final step of problem solving",
                "requires consideration of multiple criteria"
            ],
            "correctOption": "is the first step of decision making"
        },
        {
            "question": "The appropriate decision criterion is dependent on:",
            "options": [
                "The risk personality of the decision maker.",
                "The philosophy of the decision maker.",
                "The risk involved",
                "The philosophy involved"
            ],
            "correctOption": "The risk involved"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is self control?",
            "options": [
                "Listening to others",
                "Doing whatever you want",
                "Never having fun",
                "One’s will power"
            ],
            "correctOption": "One’s will power"
        },
        {
            "question": "Social entrepreneurship is characterized by?",
            "options": [
                "Risk-taking",
                "Leadership",
                "Extreme complexity",
                "Visionary"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Extreme complexity"
        },
        {
            "question": "Intense involvedness is one of the characteristic of?",
            "options": [
                "Economic entrepreneur",
                "Corporate entrepreneur",
                "Social entrepreneur",
                "Political entrepreneur"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Social entrepreneur"
        },
        {
            "question": "Accepting our weaknesses means:",
            "options": [
                "we are content to stay as we are",
                "we have the courage to change",
                "we are weak",
                "we are losers"
            ],
            "correctOption": "we have the courage to change"
        },
        {
            "question": "Successful people are usually willing to",
            "options": [
                "admit their personal weaknesses",
                "admit defeat",
                "manage their actions to bring about change",
                "look at feedback about their efforts to change"
            ],
            "correctOption": "look at feedback about their efforts to change"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you can’t predict the outcome of one of your possible choices, you should:",
            "options": [
                "Take the best alternative",
                "change policy",
                "change strategy",
                "stop and gather more information before making any decisions"
            ],
            "correctOption": "stop and gather more information before making any decisions"
        },
        {
            "question": "A _________ isn unbending intention, a single-mindedness of purpose that promises to overcome all obstacles regardless of how you may feel at any particular moment.",
            "options": [
                "Commitment",
                "Strategy",
                "Plan",
                "Blue print"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Commitment"
        },
        {
            "question": "Being industrious simply means:",
            "options": [
                "Hard work",
                "Putting in time",
                "Task",
                "Studious"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Putting in time"
        },
        {
            "question": "Lifelong learning makes use of  _____________  learning process(s).",
            "options": [
                "Formal",
                "Traditional",
                "Informal & Formal",
                "Informal"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Informal & Formal"
        },
        {
            "question": "As change agents, social entrepreneurs act in the following ways except:",
            "options": [
                "Being accountable to the constituencies served",
                "Acting boldly and responsively to tackle need",
                "Being accountable to government",
                "Adopting a mission to create social value"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Being accountable to government"
        },
        {
            "question": "Social entrepreneurs take actions as change agents by:",
            "options": [
                "Being accountable to the constituencies",
                "Acting boldly and responsively",
                "Being accountable to government",
                "Adopting a task to fashion social worth"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Adopting a task to fashion social worth"
        },
        {
            "question": "How do entrepreneurial foundations differ from foundations with a more traditional approach to philanthropy?",
            "options": [
                "They rigorously assess how the grant was spent",
                "They only fund direct costs",
                "They hold the grantee accountable for the outcomes from their grant",
                "They work with the grantee to achieve desired outcomes"
            ],
            "correctOption": "They work with the grantee to achieve desired outcomes"
        },
        {
            "question": "In addressing the 21st century challenges, what is needed?",
            "options": [
                "Creative initiatives of few",
                "Creative initiatives of only-some",
                "Creative initiatives of more",
                "Creative initiatives of many"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Creative initiatives of many"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Nigerian Stock Exchange is located in/at",
            "options": [
                "Abuja",
                "Lagos",
                "Kano",
                "Asaba"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Lagos"
        },
        {
            "question": "When a business concern is unable to pay its debts, it is said to be",
            "options": [
                "hibernating",
                "bankrupt",
                "melting down",
                "optimizing"
            ],
            "correctOption": "bankrupt"
        },
        {
            "question": "Social entrepreneur sometimes",
            "options": [
                "quit",
                "fail",
                "becomes less entrepreneurial",
                "fight"
            ],
            "correctOption": "fail"
        },
        {
            "question": "The serious barriers faced by social entrepreneurs make them:",
            "options": [
                "quit",
                "less entrepreneurial",
                "losers",
                "sometimes fail"
            ],
            "correctOption": "sometimes fail"
        },
        {
            "question": "Business entrepreneurs measure performance in profit and return but social entrepreneurs measure performance in:",
            "options": [
                "Social structure",
                "social change",
                "Social profit",
                "Social returns"
            ],
            "correctOption": "social change"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is Not an essential tool required for enterprising?",
            "options": [
                "Acquisition",
                "Endurance",
                "Empathy",
                "Resourcefulness"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Acquisition"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following are common alliances for the non-profit sector?",
            "options": [
                "Independent Sector",
                "Voluntary Sector",
                "Charity Sector",
                "Third Sector"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Voluntary Sector"
        },
        {
            "question": "A range of terms is used to describe social entrepreneurship except?",
            "options": [
                "Corporate social responsibility",
                "Philanthropy",
                "Social purpose endeavour",
                "Social wealth"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Social wealth"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following traditional marketing elements do not apply to social entrepreneurship efforts?",
            "options": [
                "Marketing Mix",
                "Public Relations",
                "Sales Promotion",
                "Place"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Sales Promotion"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who are those that create giant impact, leave a scratch on history and cause sea change movements?",
            "options": [
                "Charismatic entrepreneurs",
                "Political entrepreneurs",
                "Corporate entrepreneurs",
                "Change entrepreneurs"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Change entrepreneurs"
        },
        {
            "question": "The valuation of social improvement in a particular country is attributable to a specific intervention:",
            "options": [
                "Largely True",
                "Largely Untrue",
                "Sometimes True",
                "Sometimes Untrue"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Largely Untrue"
        },
        {
            "question": "The foundation of every business is to satisfy?",
            "options": [
                "Customs",
                "Customer",
                "Competitors",
                "Company"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Customer"
        },
        {
            "question": "Decision criteria:",
            "options": [
                "are the choices faced by the decision maker.",
                "are the ways to evaluate the choices faced by the decision maker",
                "are the problems faced by the decision maker.",
                "must be unique for a problem."
            ],
            "correctOption": "are the ways to evaluate the choices faced by the decision maker"
        },
        {
            "question": "When we choose positive beliefs, these lead to positive behaviours. Positive behaviours often lead to positive results that reinforce our positive beliefs, and the cycle begins anew. This sequence describes the cycle of",
            "options": [
                "Discipline",
                "Control",
                "Success",
                "Attitude"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Success"
        },
        {
            "question": "A time-tested tool for designing the life you want to lead is a ________, a written record of your thoughts and feelings about your past, present, and future.",
            "options": [
                "Journal",
                "Business plan",
                "Book-keeping",
                "Jotter"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Journal"
        },
        {
            "question": "When it comes to accomplishing goals, commitment creates the following except:",
            "options": [
                "Ideas",
                "Method",
                "Game-plan",
                "Control"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Control"
        },
        {
            "question": "The potential impact of women entrepreneurship  development is on :",
            "options": [
                "economic development as a whole",
                "women empowerment as a whole",
                "educational development as a whole",
                "socio-economic development as a whole"
            ],
            "correctOption": "economic development as a whole"
        },
        {
            "question": "One of these is not an “economic “obstacle to women entrepreneurship development:",
            "options": [
                "lack of access to business training in scientific/technical fields",
                "lack of perception of women as credible financial stakeholders",
                "Lack of perception of women as credible financial investors",
                "difficulties in accessing finance"
            ],
            "correctOption": "lack of perception of women as credible financial stakeholders"
        },
        {
            "question": "Perceiving reality accurately and consciously acknowledging what you perceive is?",
            "options": [
                "Readiness",
                "Knowledge",
                "Acceptance",
                "Agreement"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Acceptance"
        },
        {
            "question": "In life, there are many tasks that are not necessarily difficult but require:",
            "options": [
                "Significant assistant",
                "Significant patience",
                "Significant method",
                "Significant time"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Significant time"
        },
        {
            "question": "The continuous building of skills and knowledge throughout the life of an individual is:",
            "options": [
                "Education",
                "Experience",
                "Learning",
                "Self-motivation"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Learning"
        },
        {
            "question": "What must be established first in decision making?",
            "options": [
                "Process",
                "Standard",
                "Objectives",
                "Alternatives"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Objectives"
        },
        {
            "question": "____________   and e-commerce are terms that are sometimes used interchangeably, and sometimes they are used to differentiate one vendor's product from another.",
            "options": [
                "E-business",
                "Internet banking",
                "High communication network",
                "ATM"
            ],
            "correctOption": "E-business"
        },
        {
            "question": "Electronic commerce or e-commerce refers to a wide range of online business activities for",
            "options": [
                "Peace and service",
                "goods and products",
                "products and services",
                "deals and contacts"
            ],
            "correctOption": "products and services"
        },
        {
            "question": "E-commerce retail has not become the fastest growing trade sector to outpace every other trade and manufacturing sector since 1999.",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "correctOption": "True"
        },
        {
            "question": "E-commerce does not refer merely to a firm putting up a Web site for the purpose of selling goods to buyers over the Internet.",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "correctOption": "False"
        },
        {
            "question": "According to____________ , although the e-Commerce market in Nigeria, is relatively new, it is however growing in fast pace to attract interests of different sectors of the economy",
            "options": [
                "George Dowell (2004)",
                "Prince Osuagwu (2013)",
                "Mark Dons",
                "Rafael Nadal (2014)"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Prince Osuagwu (2013)"
        },
        {
            "question": "Businesses are started by entrepreneurs who identified that people have certain _____________  that are unsatisfied",
            "options": [
                "desires",
                "Knowledge",
                "needs",
                "All of them"
            ],
            "correctOption": "needs"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where is the commercial capital of Nigeria?",
            "options": [
                "Ibadan",
                "Aba",
                "Kano",
                "Lagos"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Lagos"
        },
        {
            "question": "Continuous development and improvement of knowledge and skills in business can be fostered through",
            "options": [
                "Networking",
                "Social Interaction",
                "Reading",
                "Learning"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Learning"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is odd?",
            "options": [
                "Merger of SMEs",
                "Long term guarantees",
                "Overdraft",
                "Concessionary financing by government agencies"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Overdraft"
        },
        {
            "question": "In financing new ventures, all except one is not applicable",
            "options": [
                "Shares sold in the open market",
                "Bank loans guaranteed by government",
                "Self-financing",
                "Grants from NGOs"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Shares sold in the open market"
        },
        {
            "question": "The major different types of e-commerce are all except one",
            "options": [
                "business-to-business (B2B)",
                "business-to-consumer (B2C)",
                "business-to-government (B2G)",
                "consumer-to-students (C2S)"
            ],
            "correctOption": "consumer-to-students (C2S)"
        },
        {
            "question": "A sound capital structure will lead to a",
            "options": [
                "Profitable business",
                "Mass acquisition of machines",
                "Productive business",
                "Competition"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Productive business"
        },
        {
            "question": "When a need is satisfied as investment worthy and a proposal is identified, the next line of action by the entrepreneur is",
            "options": [
                "Distribution plan",
                "Feasibility study",
                "Financial plan}",
                "Production plan"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Financial plan}"
        },
        {
            "question": "One source of funding available to the entrepreneur that is not paid back to the creditor is called",
            "options": [
                "Credit card",
                "Grant",
                "People-to-people lending",
                "Venture capital"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Grant"
        },
        {
            "question": "Each of us encounters____________ and____________  of business organizations as we go through the day",
            "options": [
                "browns and items",
                "products and teaching",
                "products and services",
                "services and competition"
            ],
            "correctOption": "products and services"
        },
        {
            "question": "A facility that is not provided by Government that can be exploited by SMEs is",
            "options": [
                "Concessionary financing",
                "Merger of SMEs/Industry financing agencies",
                "Long term guarantees",
                "Overdraft"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Overdraft"
        },
        {
            "question": "One of the following is a source of fund that is never typically paid back to its creditors",
            "options": [
                "Venture capital",
                "Grant",
                "Overdraft",
                "People-to-people lending"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Grant"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is odd?",
            "options": [
                "Merger of SMEs",
                "Long term guarantees",
                "Overdraft",
                "Concessionary financing by government agencies"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Overdraft"
        },
        {
            "question": "One source of funding available to the entrepreneur that is not paid back to the creditor is called",
            "options": [
                "Credit card",
                "Grant",
                "People-to-people lending",
                "Venture capital"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Grant"
        },
        {
            "question": "A facility that is not provided by Government that can be exploited by SMEs is",
            "options": [
                "Concessionary financing",
                "Merger of SMEs/Industry financing agencies",
                "Long term guarantees",
                "Overdraft"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Overdraft"
        },
        {
            "question": "One of the following is a source of fund that is never typically paid back to its creditors",
            "options": [
                "Venture capital",
                "Grant",
                "Overdraft",
                "People-to-people lending"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Grant"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is odd?",
            "options": [
                "Merger of SMEs",
                "Long term guarantees",
                "Overdraft",
                "Concessionary financing by government agencies"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Overdraft"
        },
        {
            "question": "One of these is not an “economic “obstacle to women entrepreneurship development:",
            "options": [
                "lack of access to business training in scientific/technical fields",
                "lack of perception of women as credible financial stakeholders",
                "lack of perception of women as credible financial investors",
                "difficulties in accessing finance"
            ],
            "correctOption": "lack of perception of women as credible financial stakeholders"
        },
        {
            "question": "The continuous building of skills and knowledge throughout the life of an individual is:",
            "options": [
                "Education",
                "Experience",
                "Learning",
                "Self-motivation"
            ],
            "correctOption": "Learning"
        },
        {
            "question": "E-business and e-commerce are terms that are sometimes used interchangeably, and sometimes they are used to differentiate one vendor's product from another.",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "correctOption": "True"
        },
        {
            "question": "Electronic commerce or e-commerce refers to a wide range of online business activities for",
            "options": [
                "Peace and service",
                "goods and products",
                "products and services",
                "deals and contacts"
            ],
            "correctOption": "products and services"
        },
        {
            "question": "E-commerce retail has not become the fastest growing trade sector to outpace every other trade and manufacturing sector since 1999.",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "correctOption": "True"
        },
        {
            "question": "E-commerce does not refer merely to a firm putting up a Web site for the purpose of selling goods to buyers over the Internet.",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "correctOption": "False"
        },
        {
            "question": "The study of business is both _____________ and _____________ ",
            "options": [
                "social and exciting",
                "exciting and challenging",
                "challenging and determining",
                "determining and social"
            ],
            "correctOption": "exciting and challenging"
        }
    ]
}